hey guys this looked like a fun one it's
a lot more work than I was expecting it
to be we're trying to find the area of
this orange triangle if you want to try
it on your own pause it right now cuz
I'm going to solve it in 3 2 1 we know
the three sides of this golden yellow
triangle I want to find the area of it
first and we can do that with Heron's
formula it uses the semi-perimeter which
is half of the perimeter and then you
just plug it into this formula right
here so let's do it for our Golden
Triangle for a b and c we're going to
plug in the sides 8 4 and 6 and 8+ 4 6 /
2 is equal to 9 so in the place of all
these s's I'm going to plug in 9 and
then we'll plug in 8 for the a four for
the B and 6 for the C and we can
simplify this we can bring down the 9
and all the parentheses 9 - 8 is equal
to 1 9 - 4 is equal to 5 9 - 6 is equal
to 3 so this will equal theare < TK of 9
* 15 and we can split this up into two
separate square roots > of 9 * > 15 and
theun of 9 is equal to 3 so the area of
this triangle is 3un 15 but the area of
a triangle is also equal to/ 12 base
time height where this is the height of
the triangle right here so this will
also equal 3un 15 b stands for the base
and the base of this triangle is equal
to 6 and then 1 12 * 6 is equal to 3 and
after we divide both sides by three we
get H is equal to theare < TK of 15 and
we can update this H to be square < TK
of 15 now let's bring back our orange
triangle I want to draw a line from this
vertex up here that's parallel to this
line let's make this line more bold and
let's hide this stuff for a second these
two angles are called alternate interior
angles and since these two lines are
parallel these angles are congruent to
each other and let's make this line bold
and extend it a little bit these two
angles are called vertical angles and
they are also congruent and then this
angle and this angle are called
corresponding angles since these are
parallel these corresponding angles are
going to be congruent to each other now
we can focus on this triangle right here
we have these two base angles congruent
which means this is an isoceles triangle
so this side will also have a length of
four and since this is four and the
entire side length is eight this piece
will also be four let's label the base
of our orange triangle X and now we can
use th's theorem says if you have a
triangle and a line cutting through that
triangle parallel to the base this ratio
will be true and if we put this on its
side it'll have the exact orientation of
our triangle here and we can set up our
proportion a is going to be equal to 6 B
is going to be equal to X and C and D
are both equal to 4 well the only way 6
overx is going to be equal to 4 over 4
is if x is equal to 6 so that means the
base of our orange triangle is going to
be equal to 6 and now we're ready to
find the area of our orange triangle
this height is the same as the height of
our orange triangle the area of our
triangle is 1/2 base time height where
the base is equal to 6 and the height is
equal to < TK of 15 1 12 of 6 is equal
to 3 and that's going to be multiplied
by the < TK of 15 and that's the answer
to our question we can put a box around
it so in this problem the area of this
orange triangle is equal to 3 < TK 15
square units and that is approximately
11.62 square units how exciting this was
kind of a long one if you actually
finished it comment a TV series you'd
recommend watching I need some
suggestions